Cinthia Fontoura de Souza

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Brazilian | Dublin 9 | cinthiafontouras@gmail.com +353 83 385 9229 | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Junior Software Developer enrolled in a Full Stack software development program at Code Institute, where I am learning HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. In addition, I am studying Agile Methodology, UX/UI, SEO and Web Accessibility. I am actively seeking a front-end opportunity to improve my skills. Working 14 years as a Chef, I had the chance to develop my teamwork skills in restaurants where I trained people, managed small teams and worked on my own when I ran my bakery.

KEY SKILLS

• Programming: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Python, C#, .Net, Django, MongoDB,

JQuery, Git, GitHub, Bootstrap, Flask, Node.js, PostgreSQL

• **Design:** Figma, Design Thinking, UX/UI principles

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Jan 2022 - Apr 2023 Code Institute

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Credit Rated by The University of the West of Scotland

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021 Ibat College Dublin

Professional Diploma in UX/UI Design

Distinction grade received

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

- 1. Restaurant 104 | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Hosting Ireland/cPanel.
- 2. Rock Paper Scissors Game | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, Python, Gitpod, Heroku.
- 3. JavaScript Quiz | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Gitpod, GitHub Pages.
- 4. Portfolio | Live site | GitHub | Figma, HTML, CSS, Git, Netlify.

COLLABORATIVE PROJECTS

- Emojourney | <u>Live site</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | Agile Methodology, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, GitHub Pages.
- 2. **Terra Matter** | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, GitHub Pages.
- 3. **SkillMatrix** | <u>GitHub</u> | HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, C#, .Net, Blazor, GitHub, Agile Methodology, Design Thinking.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb 2023 - Present Version 1, Dublin, Ireland

Service Desk Level 1

- Ticket management using Engage platform.
- Opsview management
- Mailboxes management

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023 Associate Consultant

Technology Ireland Digital Skillnet Academy

Nov 2021 - Jan 2023 Richmond Restaurant, Dublin, Ireland

Chef de Partie

- Michelin Bib Gourmand Restaurant since 2018.
- Preparation, control and plating meals and desserts.

May 2021 - Jan 2023 Restaurant 104, Dublin, Ireland

Web Designer

- Design, develop and maintain their <u>website</u>.
- HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Git, cPanel.

Dec 2020 - Nov 2021 Chef de Partie

- Control and organisation of kitchen stock.
- Preparation and plating meals and desserts.

CERTIFICATES AND COURSES

- IT Specialist Software Development
- ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level (2018)
- Microsoft Azure AZ-900
- CISCO Cybersecurity Essentials
- HTML and CSS (66 hours)
- Responsive websites (12 hours)
- Web Accessibility (20 hours)
- Agility: Driving Agile Transformation (6 hours)
- SEO: website optimisation (8 hours)
- Google Analytics 4: Implementation and Reporting (10 hours)
- Design Thinking: enabling solutions (8 hours)
- Technical Support Fundamentals (20 hours)
- The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking (25 hours)
- Figma: Visual design of a mobile site (10 hours)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Stamp 4 (family member) visa.
- Portuguese (Native), English (Intermediate).
- 1st Place in the Code Institute's World Emoji Day Hackathon, July 2022.